Vicky Hermawan

Yogyakarta, Indonesia



vihermawan7@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/vicky-hermawan

Summary

A workaholic person also Frontend Engineer with 3 years experience and passionate with Web Development. Skilled with React Js, Vue Js, Typescript, Go, and Node. Learn about technology professional in Diploma IV focused in Software Engineering from Universitas Gadjah Mada (UGM).

Experience



Frontend Engineer

Hijra

Jun 2022 - Present (1 year 2 months)

- 1. Maintain and review code
- 2. Optimizing size image from up 1,5 Gb reduced to 66 Mb
- 3. Develop a feature for vertical bank stream
- 4. Create pipeline to run auto deployment when developer do PR
- 5. Develop web-app for ecosystem and financing

Frontend Facilitator

Binar Academy

May 2023 - Present (3 months)

Coaching bootcamp students related to the Frontend fundamental skills, Frontend development use React Js and Redux for state management



Full Stack Developer

PT Aino Indonesia

Apr 2021 - Jun 2022 (1 year 3 months)

Full Stack Developer in Payment Segment at PT. Aino Indonesia.

Maintaining payment product such as payment gateway itself, card based settlement for various bank(E-Money, Flazz, Brizzi, Tapcash, Jakcard, etc.), Reporting, and CCHS (Central Clearing House System).

- 1. Revamp settlement engine from Java use Golang for case Jakcard and Emoney
- 2. Create ticket validation engine phase 1 for Jaklingko which process under 3 second
- 3. Create reporting system to disbursement ticketing

Full Stack Developer

BroilerX

Sep 2020 - Apr 2021 (8 months)

Responsible for development using in NodeJS, Express, GraphQL, Yarn, GitLab CI/CD, MongoDB, and React Js. Also, implement Microservices Architecture, implement Nodemailer and integrate IoT device with the system.

- 1. Revamp Saas from MUI legacy to use Antd Design
- 2. Create struturing base project to due maintainble web app
- 3. Got finalist 10 in Kemendikbud Program Mahasiswa Wirausaha 2020

Head of Riset and Technology

Koperasi "Kopma UGM"

Dec 2019 - Feb 2021 (1 year 3 months)

Responsible for the maintenance of existing networks as well as in the process of developing research and development of information systems.

Back End Developer

Pottani

Jul 2020 - Sep 2020 (3 months)

Responsible for the development of Backend using Laravel and integrate with Frontend.

Laboratory Assistant

Universitas Gadjah Mada (UGM)

Jan 2020 - Jun 2020 (6 months)

Responsible for assisting the students in Rest API at Computer and Information System Laboratory, Vocational College, Universitas Gadjah Mada.

Laboratory Assistant

Universitas Gadjah Mada (UGM)

Jan 2020 - Jun 2020 (6 months)

Responsible for assisting the students in Web Development using React Js at Computer and Information System Laboratory, Vocational College, Universitas Gadjah Mada.



Web Developer

Pusat Data dan Informasi Kementrian Sosial Indonesia

Jun 2019 - Jul 2019 (2 months)



Laboratory Assistant

Universitas Gadjah Mada (UGM)

Jan 2019 - Jun 2019 (6 months)

Responsible for assisting the students in Design Elementary at Computer and Information System Laboratory, Vocational College, Universitas Gadjah Mada.



Head Of Brand Marketing

Koperasi "Kopma UGM"

Jan 2018 - Jan 2019 (1 year 1 month)

Laboratory Assistant

Universitas Gadjah Mada (UGM)

Jul 2018 - Dec 2018 (6 months)

Responsible for assisting the students in Communication and Presentation at Computer and Information System Laboratory, Vocational College, Universitas Gadjah Mada.



Staff Brand Marketing

Koperasi "Kopma UGM" Jan 2017 - Jan 2018 (1 year 1 month)

Education



Universitas Gadjah Mada (UGM)

Bachelor's degree, Computer Software Engineering 2020 - 2022



Universitas Gadjah Mada (UGM)

Associate's degree, Computer and System Information 2017 - 2020

Licenses & Certifications



React (Basic) Certificate - HackerRank

Skills

Next.js • Docker • React.js • TypeScript • Go (Programming Language) • HTML5 • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • State Management • PHP • MySQL

Honors & Awards



Staf - Staf Terbaik Triwulan III

Sep 2018

Staf terbaik triwulan merupakan apresiasi terhadap staf di Koperasi "Kopma UGM" yang dinilai memiliki kinerja paling baik pada triwulan tersebut.